<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>iZi Knowledge Base Blog</title>
        <link>https://info.izi.community/en/blog</link>
        <description>iZi Knowledge Base Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 03:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A play-to-learn universe created for and by a liberal community]]></title>
            <link>https://info.izi.community/en/blog/04-the-journey-to-find</link>
            <guid>04-the-journey-to-find</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[iZi wants to build a liberal community by giving them access to diversity of knowledge through joy and freedom.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The journey to find knowledge is an adventure like no other. It might bring you to places filled with unexpected surprises. Within less than 2 years since our inception, iZi is proud to have paved the way for 2K+ creators to get out of their comfort zone and generate game-changing educational content. It is our joy to wake up everyday knowing that our 100K+ community of learners always learn something new on iZi. We are proud to see our previous prototypes welcomed with warmth from diverse communities, even from the early days when iZi was still a simplistic quiz-and-play website. However, this is all just a beginning.</p><p>iZi will now take you to a new chapter of our journey. It's a journey to a parallel play-to-learn universe called the iZiverse - where you have more freedom than ever to explore, garner, and apply knowledge in any aspect of life through gamification design, multi-formatted Q&amp;A content, and our brand-new rewarding mechanism. The iZiverse wants to present our community an unique opportunity - to evolve into a liberal community where users will hold the most power in giving, obtaining and creating value. We've been working hard on this for months now and are excited to share it with you!</p><h2>Our Vision</h2><p>iZi wants to build a liberal community by giving them access to diversity of knowledge through joy and freedom. At iZi, we uphold an education philosophy that obtaining knowledge best comes in the form of “unlearning and relearning” happening during disruptive psychological milestones and moments of unconditional joy. At that intersection, knowledge acquisition becomes most effective, as it takes place in a manageably chaotic, intrinsically fun, and deliberately multi-disciplinary context.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="iZiverse" src="/en/assets/images/1-ba0b410c21d89f0919eb137ba9af35ea.png" width="1456" height="485" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Isn’t it time more people have access to a proactive and delightful experience of acquiring and sharing knowledge? Isn’t it time content creators have a platform that freed them from the creative leashes and helped them to generate game-changing educational content? Isn’t it the time for people to learn, unlearn and relearn in a liberal community? iZi knows the answer. iZi IS the answer.</p><p>Freedom is at the heart of iZi’s products and community. We strive for the creation of a playground where both creators and community members freely interact within a set of ground rules. We encourage freedom from our content creators to bring unconventional educational Quests to learners within iZi’s community guidelines. We value the freedom of choice of our community members to have a say in what they want to learn and decide which creator to support. In short, iZi encourages “manageable chaos” in knowledge sharing and learning.</p><p>A suitable platform plays a pivotal role in nurturing creativity and curiosity. The iZiverse lays the foundation for the personal growth journeys of countless generations of creators and learners. Seven Lands of the universe represent a massive world filled with challenges as well as opportunities for iZi explorers to overcome themselves as we believe only through chaos can one only move forward in the journey of self-discovery. Hidden and scattered within each Land, knowledge comes in the form of Quests (multimedia and multi-format Q&amp;A games) with meticulously narrated content, adorable accompanying characters with their own personality and backstory, and attractive rewards in the form of gifts or unique opportunities.</p><h2>Product Roadmap - Q4/2022</h2><p>Quarter 4 of 2022 will mark an important milestone of iZi as we aim to end the year on a high note. Highly anticipated features will be released accompanied by important product updates that will lay the foundation for future expansions and integrations.</p><h2>iZi 5.0 - iOS &amp; Android release, Stability Monitoring and Improvement</h2><p>iZi anytime, anywhere! We are thrilled to announce that iZi is coming to your mobile devices! This is a highly requested expansion that was pushed by our community and made for our community. Interacting with iZi has never been easier. A nod to classical 8-bit gaming experience right from your pocket. Official details of iZi’s iOS and Android launch will be announced in the near future. Stay tuned!</p><p>Stability is undoubtedly one of the most important factors for the iZiverse to become a regular space for our users and a stepping stone to unlock your potential. Huge efforts have been made in all aspects, including gameplay, reward system, content creating mechanisms and admin duty. Still, we are pushing hard for that extra mile to bring the best experience to our community.</p><h2>iZi 5.1 - Multiplayer, Rating &amp; Report System, and Question Bank Updates</h2><p>The iZiverse will become truly lively in iZi 5.1, when we introduce our multiplayer mode, in which players will be invited to participate in competitive high-stake “knowledge tournaments'' held on a real-time basis. This brand-new game mode will be a significant boost to iZi’s community experience as we have noticed the desire among our community to have the appropriate stage to showcase their knowledge and compete with their friends and fellow members.</p><p>To support the multiplayer mode, a Question Bank will be added to further allow creators to contribute to our ever-expanding content database with greater ease.</p><p>Finally, to further empower our community and create a healthy environment among the iZiverse, we will introduce the Rating and Report system. Our users, both creators and learners, will have a say in vetting content quality so that the iZi Quality Control team will have a credible point of reference when it comes to nurturing and publishing suitable content.</p><h2>iZi 5.2 - Storytelling Format, Daily Mission, Social and Notification</h2><p>This is what we meant when we said that iZi will “end 2022 on a high note”. A crucial factor to a successful game is the “fun” factor - an attractive narrative and multiple game modes. As iZi continues to grow, our characters have come to life on their own and become an indispensable part of our community experience. While nothing much can be revealed at this point, we can tell that the story will be full of heart, courage and desire in the search for knowledge.</p><p>In addition, Daily Missions will be introduced to invite users to explore more side quests and be rewarded in more diverse ways for their consistent efforts of learning and sharing.</p><p>Social Features and Push Notifications will be the last features that iZi will introduce in the year of the Tiger. With this release, you can officially connect, chat and form clans with other users on the platform, and receive the latest updates on our rewarded campaigns, knowledge tournaments, and other official events directly to your home screen. We would like to call this phase “iZi Syndrome” as we encourage our community to cover social network sites with iZi presence and to never miss out on anything with our notification push.</p><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>We have a lot of work ahead of us, but we’re excited to see where this journey will take us! And the best part is still ahead of us. Stay tuned and follow iZi for the latest announcements.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>journey</category>
            <category>izi</category>
            <category>community</category>
            <category>knowledge</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Content is at the heart of iZi]]></title>
            <link>https://info.izi.community/en/blog/03-content-strategy-and-governance</link>
            <guid>03-content-strategy-and-governance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Our Content Strategy & Governance. Written by Heath Nguyen, Co-Founder & CGO of iZi.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As an educational platform with the mission “to make knowledge and opportunities accessible to all”, content is the core of our business. No matter how many pivots we make, no matter how much our universe expands, and no matter how the iZi experience becomes further and further enriched, at the heart of our strategy lies an unwavering desire to help the world learn something new with every second they spend on our platform. To uphold that commitment, it is of utmost importance to maintain the highest standards for all content that users interact with and consume during the course of adventuring our iZiverse.</p><p>Content is essential as it directly manufactures the intrinsic motivation towards learning that we want to draw out from our community members. We want to draw members in with exciting rewards and opportunities, but offer a reason for you to stay and continuously spend time on our universe with impactful, delightful, and knowledge-filled content.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ref 1" src="/en/assets/images/1-6aeecc2d6ca856bb530b5629f6edd27a.png" width="1200" height="628" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2>Our Content Strategy</h2><p>The status-quo education system has long framed our mind to view knowledge in subjects or specializations. Be it Math or History or English, we habitually treat them as separate and distinct, each with its own definition of mastery and criteria for academic success.</p><p>However, to think as such is to view education as the learning of facts. Such a view accidentally leaves out the most important aspects of training your mind to think and memorize better: creating associations and making sense of complexity. Aren’t we using English as a vehicle to learn Math? How can one claim to master Biology without a thorough understanding of organic chemical reactions at the microscopic level? Aren’t all “subjects” and “specializations'' inter-connected and deeply intertwined, since the universe and life itself are such complex and constantly evolving systems that one discipline should never prove sufficient to decode? Aren’t they just over-simplified, over-glorified and over-segregated categories of knowledge, manifested to scale up educational delivery at an industrial pace and create specialized workforces that can meet the demand of the Industrial Revolutions?</p><p>At iZi, we believe that unlearning and relearning best takes place at the intersection of disruptive psychological milestones and moments of unconditional joy. It is when the acquisition of knowledge is manageably chaotic, intrinsically fun, and deliberately multi-disciplinary. Our iZiverse is divided into 07 Lands (maps) with different knowledge themes. The themes are not subject-based, but rather covering the most essential components of an individual’s personal development: Thinking, Experiencing, Exploring, Inventing, Communicating, Working, and most importantly, Being. This structure encourages users to think more critically and always be in a mindful state about their own growth, and become less attached to the traditional tendency of categorizing themselves into “verticals”. I believe this is the fundamental distinction between developing a human being versus developing a robot.</p><p>Located in different places within each map are Quests in various categories related to that component of development. For example, in the Communicating map, there is a category of Languages and in Working, there is a category of Entrepreneurship. Every content is purpose-driven (helping you understand the Why?), practical (with real-life examples and applications), and thought-provoking (encouraging critical reflections and deep thinking).</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ref 2" src="/en/assets/images/2-30f46f7a053b3d06917e4f21d3fa1034.png" width="1600" height="1080" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2>Description of the seven maps</h2><ol><li>Map BEING: The land of exploring oneself and the meaning of existence. You can find here wisdom of philosophy, psychology, medicine, and biology that helps us understand our body, mind and heart as a whole.</li><li>Map THINKING: The land where your thoughts are trained and developed through historical and societal stories, events, facts, and figures that are viewed from a variety of critical perspectives.</li><li>Map WORKING: The land filled with diligence and passion for meaningful work. Great lessons of entrepreneurship, finance, and careers are plentiful here.</li><li>Map EXPLORING: The untraveled and scenic land, where knowledge treasures about nature, the Earth, places, and survival are hidden, waiting to be discovered by the bravest.</li><li>Map COMMUNICATING: The joyous land filled with songs and light, where languages, cultures, and arts collide and mingle to form a lively and colorful atmosphere of delight and hope.</li><li>Map EXPERIENCING: The land of knowledgeable, wise and enlightened citizens, who are well-versed in math and all basic sciences, with an advanced education system built on the foundation of free thinking and learning-by-doing.</li><li>Map INVENTING: The land of civilization, modernity and advanced industries with humanity's newest inventions. Here, you will be introduced to the most updated knowledge on technology, engineering, and innovation.</li></ol><h2>Our Content Production</h2><p>All content on iZi is created by our talented and resourceful community of Creators, and from our collaboration with selected Content Partners.</p><p>Our Creators are individuals and organizations whose accounts are verified by us. They are (teams of) teachers, educators, experts, or knowledge enthusiasts with experience and academic background related to content they contribute to our platform. They are the most fervent and skillful ambassadors of knowledge, with the ability to create content that sparks curiosity and excitement.</p><p>Our Content Partners are trusted and well-established organizations worldwide, including educational institutions, NGOs and NPOs, schools, publishers, among others. They provide accurate, diverse, and credible sources of content, exciting opportunities related to overseas studying, researching, and traveling, and in the future, official accreditation for dedicated members of our community.</p><h2>Our Content Governance</h2><p>Because of our rigorous determination to uphold our content standards, all user-generated content will go through a centralized review process that takes at maximum 30 minutes.</p><p>In addition, we use a community voting system for governance even after the content has been published successfully. In the next few months, we will be implementing an automatic system reviewed by AI and a mechanism to allow the user community to evaluate the quality of every content they engage with:</p><ul><li>First, users can rate the quality of the content using a 5-star rating scale immediately after their engagement with that content. All content with an average rating of 2 out of 5 or lower will be sent to our Quality Control team for a secondary in-depth review.</li><li>Second, there is a reporting function where users can report inaccurate, skeptical, provocative, or offensive content to iZi. All reports will be reviewed by our Quality Control team.</li></ul><h2>Our Content Distribution</h2><p>In the next phases of growing iZi, we have reserved plans to leverage artificial intelligence (AI) to provide you with a fully personalized learning path, based on your areas needing improvement and your own preferences. Suitable content will be recommended for you and curated into sequences meaningful to your personal development.</p><p>With all of the above pillars in place, we shall be deliberate and consistent in our governance of content, while gradually opening up all other components of our iZiverse, such as new maps, new characters, and new features to you, the community, to fill up and contribute with your enthused imagination and ingenious resourcefulness (view more here).</p><p>We wish to bring you a never-before-seen play-to-learn experience, as fun and free as we promised.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>content</category>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>strategy</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The People and History of iZi]]></title>
            <link>https://info.izi.community/en/blog/02-the-people-and-history-of-izi</link>
            <guid>02-the-people-and-history-of-izi</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[iZi is a gamified knowledge platform, born with a mission to “make knowledge and opportunities accessible to all”.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>iZiis a gamified knowledge platform, born with a mission to “make knowledge and opportunities accessible to all”. iZi creates joy through gamification design and reward mechanisms, and delivers educational value through diverse knowledge-sharing content in interactive question formats.</p><p>Individuals, especially students, can explore knowledge and search for opportunities on our platform through playing Quests and competing for special rewards. For organizations and enterprises, iZi provides a comprehensive solution from customized game design to content creation to help internal training and community connection become more engaging and meaningful.</p><p>iZi released its first version in February 2021 and was welcomed with enthusiasm from the content creator community, teacher community and all types of events (online and offline) from the student community from over 50 universities in Vietnam. Being a simple and friendly gamification platform to create and play quizzes, iZi attracted over 3K sets of user-generated content and 100K organic users through word of mouth just within the year.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Google Analytics" src="/en/assets/images/1-e5e2a8cb49bcfeca13d886c9ef8d3212.jpg" width="1087" height="959" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The joy and excitement from the community when using iZi nurtured our strong belief that applying gamification to knowledge sharing will be a game-changing (no pun intended) disruption to the way we teach and learn.</p><style data-emotion="css 1gtpcii">.css-1gtpcii{text-align:center;margin-bottom:calc(var(--ifm-leading-desktop) * 1rem);}.css-1gtpcii iframe{max-width:100%;max-height:calc((100vw - 40px) / (16 / 9));}</style><div class="css-1gtpcii"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iMIxR40HNwg" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>With a strong purpose to accelerate our product innovation, our iZi team has deployed 4 consecutive experimental versions (2.0, 3.0, 4.0 and 5.0) within the next 9 months. On average, we released a new version every 2 months to upgrade the playing experience such as in-game spell, in-game chat through text, audio and video, broadcasting, debates, among others. Each version was experienced by our most loyal and active group of iZi users in order to gather their feedback on both product and business model.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="iZi Version 2.0" src="/en/assets/images/2-585b2bab032fedae258d19de3dd17f6c.png" width="1600" height="844" class="img_ev3q"></p><style data-emotion="css 1duo2bc">.css-1duo2bc{font-size:12px;text-align:center;font-style:italic;}.css-1duo2bc >p:first-of-type{margin:0;}</style><div class="css-1duo2bc"><p>Version 2.0</p><p>Real-time chat through audio/video in a quiz-playing room</p></div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="iZi Version 3.0" src="/en/assets/images/3-25408d5e2b0d1d7f5ec1e84e7b3985d2.png" width="1600" height="983" class="img_ev3q"></p><style data-emotion="css 1duo2bc">.css-1duo2bc{font-size:12px;text-align:center;font-style:italic;}.css-1duo2bc >p:first-of-type{margin:0;}</style><div class="css-1duo2bc"><p>Version 3.0</p><p>Live broadcasting with real-time created quizzes and multi-streaming to different platforms</p></div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="iZi Version 4.0" src="/en/assets/images/4-8b376969aafb0dcf8d69ddf7eb7d9331.png" width="937" height="666" class="img_ev3q"></p><style data-emotion="css 1duo2bc">.css-1duo2bc{font-size:12px;text-align:center;font-style:italic;}.css-1duo2bc >p:first-of-type{margin:0;}</style><div class="css-1duo2bc"><p>Version 4.0</p><p>Pre-recorded debate videos with interactive questions playable during watching</p></div><p>Through all the experiments and in-depth conversations with our users, we understand:</p><ul><li>Most general learners care more about the learning experience rather than the content. That experience demands a lot of fun, inspiration, passion, and community connection. That is why iZi’s gameplay is designed with narrative, community-based game rules along with meaningful rewards (<a href="/en/blog/04-the-journey-to-find">read about our product roadmap here</a>).</li><li>Learners need educational content to be diverse yet relevant and consistent in quality. Thus, in the effort to create such diversity, iZi establishes partnerships with a variety of Content Partners including schools, institutions, and organizations, and also allows the community to contribute. We use a centralized review system to control the quality of content submitted by users. iZi content revolves around the topic of “career and finance”, along with other supporting topics (<a href="/en/blog/03-content-strategy-and-governance">read about our content strategy here</a>).</li><li>Furthermore, our user community also wants to be economically empowered in all social activities on our platform, from the creation and consumption of content to designing and exchanging virtual items. iZi aspires to consolidate and introduce an equitable economic mechanism for community members to be rewarded for creating educational value through content and entertainment value through designing and participating in platform activities.</li></ul><p>In October 2022, iZi 5.0 is officially released with a completely new look. Still applying the principles of gamification design, but iZi 5.0 takes the form of a classic treasure-hunting, Quest-hunting RPG game. iZi will take you back to the year 3000 B.C. when humanity had not learned to record history. In this alternate universe, you get the chance to venture 7 Lands, each with 7 narrating characters with their unique personality and backstory. Each Land represents a major theme in the personal development of our community members, including: Being, Thinking, Exploring, Working, Communicating, Experiencing and Inventing.</p><style data-emotion="css 1gtpcii">.css-1gtpcii{text-align:center;margin-bottom:calc(var(--ifm-leading-desktop) * 1rem);}.css-1gtpcii iframe{max-width:100%;max-height:calc((100vw - 40px) / (16 / 9));}</style><div class="css-1gtpcii"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rfXja72xaik" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><p>Behind the persistent efforts for these continuous improvements is a team filled with enthusiasm and passion for education, stories, and games. The iZi Team not only carries a free spirit of innovators but are also resilient and responsible warriors in their role and area of expertise.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="iZi People" src="/en/assets/images/5-0fd5991a3076a7ffc4ce720b4d113974.png" width="1456" height="1048" class="img_ev3q"></p><style data-emotion="css fumrhu">.css-fumrhu{font-size:12px;text-align:center;font-style:italic;margin-bottom:calc(var(--ifm-leading-desktop) * 1rem);}.css-fumrhu >p:first-of-type{margin:0;}</style><div class="css-fumrhu"><p>Team Linkedin Contact:</p><style data-emotion="css 1fjjulw">.css-1fjjulw a{margin-right:8px;}.css-1fjjulw a:last-of-type{margin-right:0px;}</style><div class="css-1fjjulw"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lauradaophan/">Laura</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hieu-nguyen/">Heath</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nam-q-dam/">Nam</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/khoa-hoang/">Khoa</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sonhoaing/">Son</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tram-cynthia/">Cynthia</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/h%E1%BB%93ng-%C4%91%E1%BB%97-thu-a4b53b1b7/">Hồng</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ed-pham-83722921a/">Du</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/khang-nguyen-hoang/">Khang</a></div></div><p>Fueling strength and energy for this journey are individuals who placed trust and invested in us, and continued to support us 24/7 regardless of the problem or obstacle. They are well-established entrepreneurs and investors from different places around the world, with proud contributions to our global society. They are beyond doubt a source of inspiration for us to keep moving forward with resilience in the direction of our mission.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="iZi Investors" src="/en/assets/images/6-c6fb3a82daff40a71a4eade1106b8b5f.png" width="1456" height="1048" class="img_ev3q"></p><style data-emotion="css fumrhu">.css-fumrhu{font-size:12px;text-align:center;font-style:italic;margin-bottom:calc(var(--ifm-leading-desktop) * 1rem);}.css-fumrhu >p:first-of-type{margin:0;}</style><div class="css-fumrhu"><p>Linkedin Contact:</p><style data-emotion="css 1fjjulw">.css-1fjjulw a{margin-right:8px;}.css-1fjjulw a:last-of-type{margin-right:0px;}</style><div class="css-1fjjulw"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyounghwan-kim-440934a/">Kyounghwan Kim</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryanpelz/">Bryan Pelz</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/buzzpalmer/">Buzz Palmer</a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jongheun-lee-7a4399111/">Ray Lee</a></div></div><p>We are always searching for talents with a free and fun spirit to join us in the pursuit of our mission “to make knowledge and opportunities accessible to all” through gamification. If you are who we are looking for and want to accompany us, don’t hesitate to send your coolest intro to <a href="mailto:hr@izi.community" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hr@izi.community</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>history</category>
            <category>people</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['The Why of iZi' - Laura Phan, Founder & CEO]]></title>
            <link>https://info.izi.community/en/blog/01-inspiration-and-education</link>
            <guid>01-inspiration-and-education</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA['What has led us to decisions we make?' - This question popped up in the middle of my years in university, right when I was feeling the most held down by the consequences of my own decision.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At that time, I wanted to quit school. But that meant quitting a prestigious institution along with years of hard work just to get in and considerable expectations from my family with a dream to thrive and overcome the deficient education opportunities in my home village. It also meant leaving behind all the shiny titles, track records, and accolades I had accumulated with sheer determination. I feared, with unknown reasons. I didn’t really know why I decided to apply to and pursue my studies at this university, other than “prestige and worth” - which was all everyone around me talked about. I started questioning the values of the education system that my peers and I had been embracing.</p><p>I went searching for my own answer by engaging in everything I could do outside of school. I went to many places and tried my hands at many different jobs. At a later stage in my life, I realized that was my response to “the unknown” by “unlearning and relearning”. Unlearning, to me, meant detaching all I had learned and the way I had learned, and building up completely new perspectives; while Relearning meant optimizing the learning with those new perspectives. In order to do that, I (interestingly) became a trainer with responsibilities in program design and delivery to different communities. On the path of knowing and improving myself through this profession, I continuously unlearned and relearned:</p><blockquote><p>My first unlearning and relearning: 12 years ago, I went abroad for the first time
to attend a training program from the World Bank in Coimbatore, India. Transiting
in Singapore, I was flabbergasted by a sparkling and modern Changi International
Airport, just like a futuristic world straight out of a Hollywood movie. Yet India
was a whole different story. Buses were missing doors, motorbikes looked like moving
skeletons made of steel, and raincoats were nowhere to be found! On the first day
of the program, I met 37 people from 20 countries with bewilderment and panic.
I could not speak English and could not follow any of the content that made me
feel completely helpless. On the final day of the program, I took all courage to
share with the whole class the new way of learning I designed (since I couldn’t
catch up well with the current method). Overwhelmed with happiness and surprise,
I found myself winning the creative trainer award and an official certification
(which I should not have been qualified to receive).</p><p>My second unlearning and relearning: My first overseas trip had laid a foundation
for many more trips to Asia and the U.S. within the next 02 years. I aspired to
know more, do more, and achieve more. Once again, I started on the path of obtaining
more shiny accolades and decided to found my first business with major support
from national media. I failed after one year. I was so stubborn in sticking to
what I had in an attempt to find meaning and happiness. But after all, it left
me with emptiness. I decided to unlearn and detach once again by taking on non-profit
educational missions in remote areas . During this period, I was exposed to and
became deeply influenced by the educational philosophy of Jiddu Krishnamurti and
the life philosophy of Lao Tzu. I learned to maintain my existence at the most
basic level of needs and stayed away from all sparkling yet unnecessary attachments.</p><p>My third unlearning and relearning: That year, my family went broke and my apartment
building was unfortunately burned down, which took away many lives and caused great
material damage. I was blessed to escape the incident. The next few months of living
in minimalism with just a few basic sets of clothes and 20–cent meals made me feel
enlightened and ready for all challenges to come. But once again, I fell into the
trap of over-glorifying my means. I held this false sense of elitism and thought
minimalism was the one and only way to an effective life. Moving from one end of
the stubborn spectrum (“I must have it all”) to the other (“I must have nothing”),
I realized the need to unlearn again to change my fixed mindset and find a new
balance. I rushed back into the hustle and bustle of entrepreneurship, but with
a different state of mind.</p><p>My fourth unlearning and relearning: I had a clearer understanding of my purpose
and my selection of means. I founded iZi in that liberated state of mind, with
a pure wish to make knowledge and opportunities accessible for all, helping everyone
to expand their worldview and achieve liberation. On this journey, there were times
when I was preoccupied with how others would view and use this means. I was chasing
numbers and results, and struggled to define the values my team and I wanted to
create. I decided to unlearn by a trip without any expectations to the Himalayan
mountains in Ladakh. Spending days on the snowy mountains without internet, mobile
connection and basic commodities, I lost all connections to the outer world, but
unexpectedly developed stronger connections with my inner self. In my previous
unlearnings, I was always facing major psychological changes. But this time around,
the unlearning naturally occurred through unconditional moments of joy. This newfound
self-awareness helped me stop living so much in the future and develop a wholehearted
appreciation for what is currently present.</p></blockquote><p>In this constant and ongoing process of unlearning and relearning, I have arrived at a fundamental truth: the meaning of education is “liberation”. There are so many ways to define liberation, but to me, the concept refers to self-awareness at the highest level, self-appreciation of our very being, and thorough comprehension of all consequences of all decisions to select a means of manifesting ourselves in life.</p><p><strong>Joy and liberation are values that we, through iZi, want to create for our community.</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ref 1" src="/en/assets/images/1-81e1c28e9270b133001ef77d4c0e2b7c.png" width="850" height="400" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The education we received for over 16 years did not give us that. We were taught how to use the means to have productive lives and also to identify and measure ourselves with them. We became dependent on the means instead of mastering them. This does not mean that we reject the value of schools. Quite the contrary, to us, school is one of the greatest inventions of human civilization, designed for humanity to access knowledge with greater ease. Schools fulfilled its role extremely well in times when media of communication were severely lacking.</p><p>But in the context of today, the internet, telecommunications, satellite phones and efficient global transportation networks have enabled the reception of information and the construction of new worldviews freer, more objective and more personalized than ever. Meanwhile, textbooks and teachers, no matter how well-crafted, will still face the fallacies of subjective thinking. Therefore, it is necessary to supplement knowledge acquisition (“learn”) with two very important tasks: knowledge reconstruction (“unlearn”) and optimization of knowledge acquisition (“relearn”). In which, unlearning is the most fundamental process leading to liberation and can never be separated from relearning. And this should not be a one-time process but will be ongoing throughout the entire journey of life.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ref 2" src="/en/assets/images/2-638fce823cefa0417b5195ae4ee6cb68.png" width="369" height="136" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>“Unlearn and relearn” is not a new invention but a new use of words. It is an amalgamation of human civilization that dates back almost 3,000 years ago from ancient Rome and Greece. At that time, what was discussed was an education cultivating free human beings - "liberal education". In the 19th century, the fast-paced development of industrialization and modernization pushed "liberal education" into oblivion to make way for "professional education" in most nations around the world. That was the time when education as we know it today was born and maintained for more than two centuries. “Professional education” was born to accommodate the speed at which our world needed to industrialize and modernize. That trend leads us closer to modern industrial means but further from the existential purpose (“Being”). So, learning to "unlearn" is learning to think, with the purpose of self-awareness and detachment from patterns. From that newfound thinking, we develop a more holistic worldview, and thereby form wisdom.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ref 3" src="/en/assets/images/3-03a9817ce333e54e60d314af03e069a1.png" width="1600" height="297" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Unlearning and relearning can never be separated. There are two points in time most suitable for it: life events with major psychological changes and moments of unconditional joy. The former don’t happen all that often, but the latter can. That is why our guiding educational philosophy is to bring joy for our learners to accelerate the unlearning process, so that learners can obtain self-awareness and liberation. Only when liberation is achieved can “relearning” have its full effect, which is also when iZi rewards our learners with practical opportunities to make use of their means for a better livelihood and achieve their purpose of being. iZi was born with a wish to accompany schools, education institutions and the ecosystem of relevant partners on the path towards consolidating and developing the meaning of education which I have contemplated and longed to share with communities all over the world.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Ref 4" src="/en/assets/images/4-e4a3769bda568a56c7f3dd60e2a5c42b.png" width="1254" height="382" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>inspiration</category>
            <category>education</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>